Leonardo Rafael Pérez Martínez

Psychologist-Social psychology

Av. Intercomunal de Antímano con Calle El Carmen Caracas, Municipio Libertador

\$\infty\$ +58 416 4272880

\$\infty\$ +58 212 4727982

\$\infty\$ leo.prez.k@gmail.com

in psic-leonardo-pérez

\$\infty\$ Stringdom42



Professional profile

Social psychologist with advanced computer skills. Design and management of social incidence projects. Experienced speaker. Expert on group dynamics, training and evaluation. Writer and editor of technical, promotional and instructional content with experience on online platforms. Specialized in sexual and reproductive rights, education and health.

Skills for budget management and performance indicators monitoring. Visual communication design, video and audio editing. Organization of groups of people and communications management. Experience with youth engagement, advocacy groups and social network communications.

Work experience

Nov, 2019-Current

CEX/CIES, Member of the technical committee of the center of excellence in comprehensive sexual education, Bolivia.

Volunteer role.

- Validation of educational content for the online comprehensive sex education course for family planning services providers.
- Selection of a CSE toolbox with quality educational content.
- Monitoring youth engagement and participation projects.
- Consultorship for the center of excellence members on sexual and reproductive health and rights issues.
- Remote participation on the tecnical committee assemblies.

Sep, 2017-Current

PLAFAM, A.C, Program specialist for youth and adolescents engagement.

- Social projects management for youth and adolescents engagement and participation, promotion of comprehensive sex education, family planning and empowerment on sexual and reproductive health and rights.
- Organization of youth volunteer activist group "Plafam Juvenil".
- Promoting and managing youth participation inside and outside of the organization.

- Management and tracking of institutional alliances with other non-profits, education centers, youth groups, and both private and government community associations.
- Planning and delivery of education activities for people with contact and influence over youth, e.g. teachers, parents, medics, nurses, youth leaders and other adults of influence.

Feb-Aug, 2017 **teleSUR, La nueva televisión del sur, C.A**, Web content writer.

- Writer of research articles on historical and current events.
- Writer of content for the channel's web page.
- Summary of news events.
- Creation of informative notes of interviews.
- Writing, design and scheduling of promotional notes for the channel's programming grid.

2015-2017 **Kavanayentech C.A.**, APIA Documentum tehcnology implementation consultant.

- Psychology consultant on change management and technology adoption in the public administration.
- o APIA Documentum implementation and development team oversight.
- Design and implementation of training workshop for public administration staff on the use of informatic technologies.
- Design and management of a technology adoption plan and change management for the use of the APIA Documentum software package in public administration.
- Design, application and analysis of technology adoption and organization change assestment instruments.

2010-2015 **IBM de Venezuela C.A.**, 'Business innovation center' operator.

- Monitoring informatic processes on the national interbaking network.
- Detection, management and monitoring of the platform incidents.
- Execution of routine and maintenance processes.
- Scheduling and executing routine maintenance of datacenter computer equipment.
- Assistance to software developers and datacenter's technical maintenance staff.

2010-2011 The Adecco Group Venezuela—Banco Mercantil, Help-desk analyst.

- Provided technical informatic support for Mercantil Bank staff.
- Friendly and comprehensive customer call reception.
- Monitoring and management of technical support tickets.
- Tecnical assistance to administrative informatic processes.
- Effective remote support for tecnical malfunctions.

Education

2018 Degree in Psychology, specializing in Social Psychology,

Universidad Central de Venezuela, Equivalent to bachelor's degree.

Software skills

Microsoft Office Advanced use of Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Project.

HitFilm Express Video editing, color correction and sound synchronization.

Reaper DAW Advanced edition of audio, musical composition and mixing, noise reduction

and effects processing.

Adobe Photoshop Image editing, photographic composition, correction and design.

Git Advanced version management and collaborative remote work.

MEXTypesetting Advanced and automated creation of high typographic quality documents. software

Languages

Spanish Native.

English Fluent reading, writing and speaking skills.

Project management

Mar-2020 Training health care providers in sexual and reproductive rights and health.

May-2020 Virtual training route on youth sexuality for teenage girls.

July-2020 Promoting friendly comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care for

adolescents in the state of Miranda, Venezuela during the Covid-19 pandemic.

2018-2020 Developing an integral model for attention and prevention of the Zika virus

syndrome: a sexual and reproductive health approach.

2017-2018 "Háblalo": raising awareness and facing stigma against abortion in Venezuela

through audio-visual messages.

2016-2017 "Cero prejuicios, PLAFAM habla contigo": promotion of comprehensive sex

education inside schools of Caracas, Venezuela.

2015-2016 APIA Documentum: Pilot implementation for digital certification processes of

ID documents in SAREN's Caracas main registry.

Personal references

Nelmary Diaz — Program manager, PLAFAM, A.C.

Email: ndiaz@plafam.org.ve

Phone: +58 412 954 9116 / +58 212 634 0177

Gustavo Torres — Founder and executive director, Kavanayentech, C.A.

Email: gtorres@kavanayentech.com

Phone: +1 786 487 7791